## **WAYNE YOUNG**

LEARNER | ACHIEVER | ANALYTICAL | RESPONSIBILITY | INTELLECTION

#### **SUMMARY**

Technology Professional with proven success in product management, software development, product delivery and customer success in IoT, Smart Buildings, Construction and Workforce Automation domains. Proactive manager with 15 years Agile development experience. Servant Leader who works well with all internal and external stakeholders to build collaborative, positive and transparent teams. Diverse, broad background that encompasses exceptional work ethic and technical ability. Noted for leadership skills, problem solving, and ability to build and deliver large, complex systems within budget and on schedule. Enjoys understanding client needs and working together to identify solutions to ensure client success and value.

#### CONTACT

PHONE:

214.316.2774 (C)

LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/wayneyoung-1190301/

**EMAIL:** 

wayne@rwysolutions.com

## **SKILLS**

- ✓ SAFe Agile Certified PO/PM
- ✓ Business Analysis
- ✓ Requirements Analysis
- ✓ SaaS/DevOps/Azure/SQL/Office 365
- ✓ BIM / 3D Visualization / Autodesk
- ✓ Building Automation Systems
- ✓ Written & Verbal Communication
- ✓ Stakeholder Management
- ✓ Account Management
- ✓ Defect Resolution
- ✓ Product Roadmap Development
- ✓ Workforce Management
- ✓ AI/ML

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Shepherd University**

Shepherdstown, WV, USA

**Bachelors of Science** 

Business Administration (Major) Computer Science (Minor)

#### **RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Technical Product Owner

June 2022- Present

Johnson Controls

- ✓ Facilitated global teams of engineers, architects, and IT professionals to deliver the OpenBlue Cloud Platform which included Digital Twin, 3D visualization, IoT sensor telemetry data for monitoring energy usage, alarms, video and predictive analysis
- ✓ Conducted Agile ceremonies and performed scrum master duties including sprint planning, daily stand-ups, retrospectives and PI planning to promote effective teamwork and project execution
- ✓ Decomposed complex project requirements and use cases into actionable features, user stories, and acceptance criteria
- ✓ Led SAFe Agile Transformation process for OpenBlue Cloud Platform team utilizing Jira, Confluence and Miro
- ✓ Certified SAFe Agile technical product owner
- ✓ Collaborated with product managers and business analysts to define and deliver product roadmap
- ✓ Familiar with building automation systems and technologies including BACNet, Modbus, PLCs, OpenBlue Enterprise Manager, Cloud, Bridge, Metasys, and others
- ✓ Created Epics, User Stories, Defects, Spikes and prioritized, maintained and updated agile backlog list in Jira
- ✓ Technologies used: Jira, Confluence, Miro, GitHub, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, Postman, Insomnia, TypeScript, NodeJS, Angular, Jira, GitHub, Autodesk Forge, BIM360, ACC, SAFe Agile

#### RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Partner Executive

Jan 2020- June 2022

Trimble E-Builder

- ✓ Partner Sales Executive responsible for winning new business, executing on existing business and expanding partner capabilities with E-Builder Construction Program Management SaaS solution
- ✓ Performed Key Sales and Account Management functions for major client/partner AEC firms
- ✓ Expanded utility client relationships and closed new business
- ✓ Developed strategic plans, lead pursuits and negotiated and managed contracts and Enterprise License Agreements
- ✓ Identified and pursued new client, partner and opportunity development initiatives

## **CONTACT**

PHONE: 214.316.2774 (C)

EMAIL:

wayne@rwysolutions.com

#### **SKILLS**

- ✓ JIRA
- ✓ Confluence
- ✓ Scrum
- ✓ Postgres/GraphQL/SQL
- ✓ Postman
- ✓ Oracle
- ✓ SQLServer
- ✓ Autodesk Forge
- ✓ Python
- ✓ IoT
- ✓ Meter Data Management
- ✓ Energy
- ✓ Water
- ✓ AMI / AMR
- ✓ APIs

✓ Operational and strategic liaison with AEC partners and leads pursuits and engagements across North America

# Director, Water Technology Sales & Development Dec 2015 – Oct 2019 iHydrant.com (Nighthawk/McWane)

- ✓ Led agile product development of innovative real-time water pressure network monitoring solution (iHydrant)
- ✓ Utilized Jira to create Epics, User Stories, Defects, Spikes and to prioritize, maintain and update product backlog list
- ✓ Managed the implementation of SaaS iHydrant complex projects for multiple clients
- ✓ Instrumental in developing and implementing mobile and webbased software/hardware solutions
- ✓ Worked closely with manufacturing to ensure ontime delivery of hardware technology
- ✓ Delivered successful pilots with San Francisco Water, Redmond, Bend, SCWD and others
- ✓ Closed large, complex SaaS deal with Los Angeles Department of Water & Power
- ✓ Identified new uses of GPS, LTE and IoT sensor technology
- ✓ Conducted Agile ceremonies and performed scrum master functions including daily stand-ups, sprint planning, backlog refinement, retrospectives
- ✓ Technologies used: Jira, .NET, CSS/HTML5, JavaScript, NodeJS, Angular, SQL Server, Jira, GitHub, GPS, LTE, Agile

#### **Solutions Director**

Nov 2010 – Dec 2015

Clevest, Inc.

- ✓ Managed an Application Development, Delivery and Support team (Developers, Analysts and Testers)
- ✓ Closed complex solution sales with largest IOUs in U.S. including AEP, FirstEnergy, Eversource, Consumers, TECO and others
- ✓ Increased product line sales 3X after acquisition from Neptune Technology Group
- ✓ Partnered with Trimble to build new AMR ruggedized handheld
- ✓ Successfully managed FirstEnergy and Allegheny Energy merger of multiple enterprise systems
- ✓ Sold solution offerings to executive-level decision makers
- ✓ Technologies used: .NET, CSS/HTML, JavaScript, SQL Server, PL/SQL, Oracle, PowerBuilder, C++, ESRI, GPS

## **Development Manager**

Nov 2003 - Nov 2010

Neptune Technology Group

- ✓ Led full system lifecycle from RFP stage to go live including pre-sales, consulting, executive sales, presentations, scope of work, contract negotiation, development, implementation, customer support and post-deployment enhancement requests for large enterprise projects
- ✓ Managed Development, Delivery and Support team of 12 (Developers, Analysts and Testers)

- ✓ Managed diverse group of developers, principal engineers and support staff
- ✓ Led SDLC team and agile transformation from waterfall development
- ✓ Implemented web-based time tracking system to accurately account for time spent on projects and to assist with planning of future projects
- ✓ Provided technical sales support and RFP/RFQ assistance
- ✓ Technologies used: Agile, Jira, Oracle, PL/SQL, C++, .NET, HTML, PowerBuilder, GPS, Google Maps, SAP & CC&B interfaces

## Senior System Engineer

March 1996 - Nov 2003

DBMicroware/Neptune Technology Group

- ✓ Designed custom workforce management workflow-based software for utilities
- ✓ Created detailed project plans in MS Project with well-defined tasks, milestones, client sign-offs, test cycles, and specifications, which served to communicate project progress to management
- ✓ Developed multi-threaded code resulting in 75% decrease in processing time
- ✓ Technologies used: Oracle, PL/SQL, SQL Server, Watcom SQL, HTML, PowerBuilder, C++